Ben Hanson

Senior Analyst

Contact Details

07557440809 ben.hanson1991@googlemail.com

Skills

Highly driven and analytically minded data analyst and reporting professional with 7 years experience. I have Strong experience in SQL coding, designing & implementing datamarts used for analytics and building Power BI reports. My experience as an analyst has equipped me with problem solving and analytical thinking skills which I believe will be useful for understanding business requirements and building databases which meet the client's needs.

Experience

The John Lewis Partnership / Senior Analyst

May 2019 - PRESENT, Bracknell

Working within the Waitrose domain, my role is to support the Category Managers & Buying teams with insights about our customer's purchase behaviours. The insights would support Category Managers in diagnosing opportunities for growth within their category. Within this role, I was responsible for designing and building BI reports, in using Google tools for the Category managers and building bespoke datamarts on their Bigquery Google Cloud platform

Allianz Insurance Plc / Portfolio Analyst

August 2013 - May 2019, Guildford

Responsible for managing 14 national Private Car and Household brokerage accounts for the Allianz UK Retail portfolios. I was responsible for analysing the customer profile through each broker, understanding the claims performance of our customers and recommending pricing and underwriting changes to the Pricing Committee. In June 2017, I was identified by the business to help launch three new digital insurance products. Utilising my SQL skills, I worked closely with IT database developers to design and implement datamarts for reporting.

Education

Swansea University/ BSc Economics

September 2010 - June 2013

Obtained 2:1 degree in BSc Economics from Swansea University.